Guide to the Preservation Department, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Preservation Department records, 1951-2015; Accession 2016-A-024
  - Conservation Division Procedures, 1984, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Conservation Division Staffing / Development of Collections Care, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Conservation Memoranda, 1974-1987 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Conservation Proposals, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Conservation Quarterly Meetings, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Conservation Department, 1973-1986 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - RLG Collections Conservation Questionaire, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Cons Studio Public Interactions 1986 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Food Policy, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Cons Studio - Inks - Marking Special Collections, 1976-1979 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Cons Studio - Binding Space and Repair, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Conservation Binding Contracts 1985, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Final Report of CCC on Technical Services 1983 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Cons Studio - Time Studies - 1983/1985 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Cons Studio - Surveys - Forms, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Cons Studio - Pres Survey - NEH - Stack Plans, masters, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report 1983-1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report 1989-1991 - Cons Studio (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report 1991-1992 - Cons Studio (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Annual Stats - FY 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Annual Report 1993/1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Annual Report 1994/1995, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Conservation 1978, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Conservation Division 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Conservation Division 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Cons Div 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Cons Div 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Cons Div 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Conservation Division 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cons Div 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Conservation Division 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Conservation Supply List 1992 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Conservation Division 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Conservation Division 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Conservation Program 1994-1995 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Conservation 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Conservation, Annual Statistics
    - 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Pres Dept / Consv Lab 2002-2006 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Constu - Statistics 1997-2004 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Constu - Standard Materials List 1973 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Conservation Studio Recipe Rev 1994 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Constu Recipies, Master, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Constu Book Marks, 198? (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Constu - Workshops - Presv. Orientation 1985 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Constu - Workshops - Commercial Binding 1992 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Constu Workshop - Simple Book Repair 1986 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Constu Workshops- 3 Conservation Preservation Acitvities, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Constu - Workshops - Jane Greenfield, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Conservation Pamphlets: "Preservation: Your…" (MASTER Copy), 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Constu - Pamphlets - Conservation and Preservation at Yale Master, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Cons Stu - Pamphlets "The Care and Handling of Books" Script Masters, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Cons Stu - Pamphlets; Greenfield, Jane - "Oriental Type Binding" - Master, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Cons Stu - Pamphlets - "Paper and its Treatment" - Master, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Cons Stu - Pamphlets - Greenfield, Jane, "Single Signature Pamphlet" - Master, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Cons Stu - Pamphlets - Greenfield, Jane, "Folding Manuscript Box" - Master, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Cons Stu - Pamphlets - "Commercial Library Binding" - Script Masters, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Cons Stu - Pamphlets - "Simple Repairs for Library Materials" - Script masters, Circa 1980s (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Conservation - Annual Reports - Fiscal Years 1974-1983 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Conservation - Lada-Macarski and Conserv Lab History, 1959, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Conservation, Correspondence-General
    - 1973 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - 1974 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - 1976 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - 1977 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - 1978 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - 1979 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - 1980 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Conservation - Correspondence - Greenfield - 1981 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Conservation - Correspondence - Greenfield - 1982 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Conservation - Correspondence - Greenfield - 1983 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Conservation - Studio Plans 1973 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Conservation - Cary Institute - proposed, 1976, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Pamphlet Count and Correspondence, 1981, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Conservation - Pamphlets - Mylar Pocket Correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - Conservation Annual Report 1974-75, 1974, 1978-79 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - Conservation - Development of instructional pamphlets, Circa 1954 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - Presv Dept - Brittle Book Survey: Current Collecting Practices 1977 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - NEH Paper - submitted for publication to College and Research Libraries (CR, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Survey Article / CR, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - General Survey (1985 NEH / CR, 1979, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Survey Final, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Survey Current Folder 1 of 2, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Survey 1983 Folder 2 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Survey tabulated, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Extra Materials, 1964-1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - BY-BZ Gay Walker Survey, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Pres Dept - Brittle Book Survey / Publication - correspondence 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Pres Dept - Brittle Book Survey / Environmental Survey Record Keeping 1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Presv Dept - Brittle Book Survey 1977 / Floors and Codes 1-3 Sterling (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Presv Dept - Brittle Book Survey 1977 / Math Library 45, 1977, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Presv Dept - Brittle Book Survey 1977 / International Law Library 48 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Presv Dept - Brittle Book Survey Classic, Circa 1977 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Presv Dept - Brittel Book Survey Floors 3M to 4 Sterling 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Presv Dept Brittle Book Survey Floors 5 to 7 Sterling Folder 1 of 2, Circa 1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Presv. Dept. - Brittle Book Survey Floors 5 to 7 Sterling Folder 2 of 2, Circa 1977 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Presv. Dept. Brittle Book Survey Music 49, Circa 1977 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Preservation - Yale Collection Survey - NEH 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - NEH Grant Proposal 1987 All other C plus Y/CBU (Berkeley) Considerations [Reformatting], 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - NEH Training the Trainers Proposal Part II 1991 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - NEH II 1982-1985 Proposal [Training Grant], 1981 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - NEH - Intern Training Classical Readings [1980], 1937-1976 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - NEH - Intern Training Preservation Reading II [1980], 1976-1981 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - NEH - Intern Training Preservation Reading III [1980], 1972-1979 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - East Asian Project CPMP 1986-1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Brittle Books 1987-1993, 1970-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mellon Internship 1987, 1987 September-December (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - NEH Grant for Preservation Administrative position 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - New Grant PS-2083-87 Preservation Administrator Position / Reports to NEH 1989 - 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Grants Memos - General 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - NEH Mircrofilming 1988 / Project Organization (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - NEH Grant - European History, Early Draft "Microfilming Project" (EHMP), 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - NEH "European History Microfilming Project" (EHMP) 1987 Grant Drafts and Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - NEH EHMP Corresp. W / NEH / 1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - NEH EHMP Cataloging / Workflow 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - EHMP - Workflow - Instructions Folder 1, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - EHMP - Workflow - Instructions Folder 2, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - EHMP - Workflow - Instructions Folder 3, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - NEH Grant - Publicity 1988, 1987, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - NEH EHMP Vendors - National Underground Storage 1988-1992 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - EHMP Vendors -Yale (Suppliers and Equipment), 1987 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - EHMP - Vendors - Yale - Renovation of Room 40, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - EHMP Vendors - Micrographic Systems of CT Correspondence, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - EHMP Corresp Misc 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - EHMP Cost Anlysis 1988 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - NEH - European History Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - EHMP - Correspondence with Yale Grants and Contracts 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - EHMP Grant # 2 1988 Drafts and Correspondence Folder 1 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - EHMP Grant # 2 1988 Drafts and Correspondence Folder 2 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - EHMP Grant # 2; NEH Corresponence, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - EHMP Grant # 2; Drafts and Correspondence with maps component 1988, 1988, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - EHMP Memos re: Personnel and Workflow, 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - EHMP / NEH Personnel - Job Descriptions 1991, 1989, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - EHMP - NEW Extension Request 1992 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - EHMP Grant # 3 Request for Proposal 1992 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - EHMP #3 and Grant Copy; Correspondence with NEH, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - EHMP Grant #3 Drafts and Corresp 1992 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - EHMP Mellon Proposal March 1992 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - European History - Mellon, 1988-1992 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - EHMP Statistics and Reports 1988 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - EHMP Statistics and Reports 1989 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - EHMP Statistics and Reports 1990 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - EHMP Statistics and Reports 1991 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - EHMP Final report to NEH and extra copies, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - EHMP - Extension Report 1994, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Future Grant Possibilities 1990 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Mellon Intern 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - NEH Meeting, 1991 November (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - NEH Press Releases, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - French History Microfilm Project (FHMP), 1993 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - FHMP Budget Cost Share, 1990-1993 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - FHMP RLG Reports, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - FHMP Contract for Microfilming, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence to/from Research Publciations, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to/from Research Publications - FHP, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - FHMP Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - FHMP Grant Proposal French, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - FHMP Grant Proposal, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - FHMP Procedures, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - FHMP NEH French History, 1989, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - FHMP Procedures (RPI), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - FHMP RFP, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - FHMP Quarterly Report, 1991-1993 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - FHMP Staff, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - FHMP Final Report, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - French Language and Literature Proposal, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - GRL 1991, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - NEH South East Asian Film Project Contributed Titles 1991, 1988-1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - NEH: Southeast Asian Collection / Presv, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Microfilming - Yoshodo - Japanese Microfilming 1991 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Photocopy Guidelines 1991 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Photocopy Instructions 1991 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Presv. Move, Undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Prospective Projects 1992 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Western Americana Preservation Project (WAPP) - NEH Application, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Western Americana Preservation Project (WAPP) - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Western Americana Preservation Correspondence 1993, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - WAPP Western Americana Preservation Project 1993, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - NEH Final Reports Western Americana 1994, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - NEH Brittle Books, 1987, 1994-1995 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - NEH Grant / Microfilming, General, 1979, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - ATLA Serials Project (American Theological Lib Assoc) 1993 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - ATLA, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Project Open Book Folder 1 of 2, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Project Open Book Folder 2 of 2, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Project Open Book (Report), 1994-1996 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Project Open Book-Publications, 1992-1995 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Mellon - Backlog Project, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Cooperative Microfilming Project (CPMP) - Correspondence 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - CPMP Grant Proposal II, 1983-1989 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Great Collections (Microfilming) Project (RLG - GCMP) - Phase I and II, 0 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - GCMP (RLG) I - Reports, quarterly 1989 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - RLG Pres. Steering Committee GCMP - 1987 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - NEH Great Collections Phase III 1993, 1987, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - NEH RLG GCMP II Film Log - Univ of Florida, Circa 1990 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - RLG Grant Proposal GMCP III, 1991-1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - RLG GCMP III 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - GCMP III Final Budget, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - GCMP IV (RLG), 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - NEH and Other Preservation Microfilming Projects, 1987, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Subjects for Proposal and Decision Making (Gay Walker files), 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Handouts (NEH Grant) 1980 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - NEH Brittle Books Meeting - 1993 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - NEH Grant, American Literature Background, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - ALPP (American Library Preservation Project) Draft Proposal 1998, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - ALPP - NEH, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - NEH ALPP New Reports 1998, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Social Science Microfilm Project / SSMP Advisory Council, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - SSMP - Ephemera Soc Sci Microfilm Project, Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - SSMP Contract Attachments, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - SSMP - Contract Memos, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - NEH Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - SSMP Correspondence (Other), 1992 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - SSMP Job Description, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - SSMP Masters, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - SSMP Meetings, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - SSMP Memos, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - SSMP Procedure, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - SSMP Proposal Info, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - SSMP Publicity, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Social Science (Project Reports), 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - SSMP Staff Performance, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - NEH SSMP, 1992-1996 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - SSMP Extension, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - SSMP Closeout, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - NEH Political Science and History of Economics, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - NEH British History Preservation Project 1998-2000 Application and Budget, 1994-1997 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - BHMP - Grant Proposal - 1994, 1989-1998 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - British History Preservation Project (BHPP) Grant Application - 1994 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - BHPP: Revised Budget and Workplan, 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - British History Microfilm Project (BHPP) 1995 Insurance (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - BHPPI - NEH Comments, 1995, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - BHPP - MSC and RPI, 1994, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - British History Preservation Project / Correspondence 1995-1996 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - BHPP Request for Proposals 1994 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - BHPP Cost Share, 1995, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - British History Project (BHPP) Microfilming RFP's, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - British History Pres. Project I, 1995,1997 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - British History (BHPP), 1995 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - British History - NEH - 1998, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - BHPP I Interim Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - BHPP I - Budget and Admin of, 1995, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - BHPP Budget Copies, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - NEH Grant Budget, 1994-1998 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - British History Project Retrospective Conversion, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - BHPP - Publicity, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - NEH - Notes on BHPP, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - British History Presv. Project II - Prep, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - British History Presv Project II - Final, 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - British History Presv Project II - Grant Evaluation, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - BHPP2 PA-23245-98, 1997-1999 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - BHPP2 Research, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - BHPP2 - quarterly reports, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - BHPP / Final Report, Undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - BHPP - Beatrice (Report) / Bibliography YDS Library Materials in BHPP, Circa 1998 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - BHPP2 - Draft Proposal, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - BHPP II / Job Descriptions - 1998 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - BHPP II - Procedure Manual, Undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - NEH Grant - Background and Prep for "Discovery, Exploration and Travel" Preservation Project 1999-2001, 1993-2001 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - NEH 2000 "Discovery, Exploration…" (unsuccessful application)., 1998-2001 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - America: Discovery, Exploration and Travel" / NEH 2001 (Not funded), 1999-2001 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - IMLS Grant - Interns/Fellows, 2008-2012 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - South Africa Now (Video) - Arcadia - July 2011-Aug 2012, 2011-2013 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Binding - Commercial - Policy and Agreements 2007-2014 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Preservation Department Budgets
    - 2000-2002 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - 2003-2006 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - 2005-2007 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - 2003-2008 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - 2007-2009 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - 2007-2009 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - 2010-2011 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Digital Conversion Facility - DCF - 2000-2006 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - YUL - Digital Production and Integration Program (DPIP) 2006-2008 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Scanning / Digital 2006-2008 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Presv Exhibit Program - Sterling includes 2008 Task Force, 2006-2012 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Presv - Exhibits Task Force, 2013-2014 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Fire Protection (Reports), 2000, 2011 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Fire Test - Trays / Shelving Restraints, 2010 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Fire Test - FM Global 2010 - Forum for Healthcare and Educ. Leaders (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Fire test - High Density Lib Storage 2005-2009 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Preservation Committee 2004-07, 2003-2005 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Presv. Policy Food and Drink, 2004-2008 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Presv - Preservation Week / Activity, 2011-2012 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Patron Education Awareness / Various Research Institutions, 1999, (2004) (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Preservation Space Planning 2007 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Presv. Dept. Renovation 2009-2010, 2008-2009 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Presv. Dept. Space Planning 2013 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Presv. Dept. - 344 Winchester Plans, 2013-2014 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - SML Stacks Cleaning - Pilot Project 1998 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - SML Stack Cleaning 1999/SMP July bids (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - SML Stack Cleaning II 2005 Bids (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - SML Stacks Cleaning II - 2005, 2005-2006 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - YUL - Strategy and Planning, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - YUL Strategic Planning 2002 Group Reports, 2001-2002 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Walker, Gay SPEC Kit 1977, "Preservation of Library Materials", 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Walker, Gay Publications, Preservation at Yale Univ. Library 1972-1982 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Preservation Subcommittee, Report to the Univ. council Comm 1977 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Emergency Planning, 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Pres Dept - Interns, Southern CT State Univ 1996 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Serials Preservation Project, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Serials Backlog Project 1995-1996; Summer Project, 1996, 1994-1996 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Microform Task Force - Final Report 1972-1978 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Audio-Visual Materials
    - "NEA / Yale "Simple Repair"
      - Slide Carousel, Circa 1980s (Box 15)
        - Audiocassette, Circa 1980s (Box 15a)
    - "Care and Handling"
      - Slide Carousel, Circa 1980s (Box 16)
      - Audio Cassette, Circa 1980s (Box 16a)
    - "Commercial and Library Binding"
      - Slide Carousel, Circa 1980s (Box 17)
      - Audio Cassette, Circa 1980s (Box 17a)
    - Video Cassette "Library", Circa 1980s (Box 18)
    - "Video Cassette "Library Dub", Circa 1980s (Box 19)
    - Reel Tape, "Care and Handling of Books" (Master 3/34 ips), Circa 1980s (Box 20)
    - Reel Tape, "Simple Repairs for Books" (Dubbing Master 3/34 ips), Circa 1980s (Box 21)
    - Reel Tape, "Simple Repairs for Books" (Original Master 15 ips), Circa 1980s (Box 22)
    - Audio Cassette, "Simple Repairs for Lib Materials" (with slide-change pulse signal), Circa 1980s (Box 23)
    - Audio Cassette, "Care and Handling of Books"/Final Version (non-pulsed), Circa 1980s (Box 24)
- Records of Bobbie Pilette, Director of Preservation, Accession 2018-A-026
  - Computer files [Born digital], 2018-A-0026-0001; 1 (Box 1)
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
- NEH Condition Survey, 1979-1982; Accession 2018-A-048
  The materials are open for research.
  - Grant proposal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tape reel, Undated (Box 2)
  - Tape reel, Undated (Box 3)
  - Tape reel, Undated (Box 4)